Guide to the New York City Central Labor Council Records WAG.049
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Manpower Utilization Council to World's Fair (1963);General files: includes Non-partisan Committees (1964);NYCCLC Executive Board Meeting sign-in sheets (1971-1979), 1963-1964, 1971-1979 (Box 182)
- Affiliations, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 1)
- Allied Printing Trades Council of Greater New York, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 2)
- American Federation of Labor, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 3)
- American Federation of Labor: Bulletins, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 4)
- American Federation of Labor: United Labor Policy Committee, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 5)
- A: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 6)
- Bakers, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 7)
- Board of Education, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 8)
- Board of Estimate, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 9)
- Building and Construction Trades Council, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 10)
- B: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 11)
- Cancer Committee: New York City, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 12)
- Central Bodies, 1951-1952 (Box 183, Folder 13)
- Central Trades and Labor Council of Greater New York and Vicinity, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 14)
- Circular Letters, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 15)
- City Council, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 16)
- City of New York: Bureau of the Budget, 1953 (Box 183, Folder 17)
- City of New York: City of Planning Commission, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 18)
- City of New York: Office of Civil Defense, 1950-1951 (Box 183, Folder 19)
- City of New York: Department of Commerce, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 20)
- City of New York: Mayor, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 21)
- City of New York: Mayor's Committee on Management Survey, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 22)
- City of New York: Mayor's Joint Committee on Port Industry, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 23)
- City of New York: Sub-Committee on Career and Salary Plan, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 24)
- City of New York: Sub-Committee on Hospitals, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 25)
- City of New York: Department of Traffic, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 26)
- City of New York: Department of Welfare, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 27)
- City of New York: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 28)
- City of New York: Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 183, Folder 29)
- Civil Service, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 30)
- Civil Service Committee, J. Sullivan, Chairman, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 31)
- CIO Council, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 32)
- Collins, William: Bon Voyage Luncheon, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 33)
- Community Chests and Councils of America, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 34)
- Cornell University: School of Industrial and Labor Relations, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 35)
- Correspondence to Central Trades and Labor Council of Greater New York from Various Unions re: Personnel Changes, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 36)
- Credentials: Delegates, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 37)
- C: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 38)
- Dinners, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 39)
- D: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 40)
- Egg Inspectors Union, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 41)
- Executive Board, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 42)
- E: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 43)
- Federal U.S. Congress, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 44)
- Firemen, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 45)
- F: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 46)
- Governor, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 47)
- Greater New York March of Dimes, 1951-1952 (Box 183, Folder 48)
- Greetings, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 49)
- Griffenhagen Report, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 50)
- G: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 183, Folder 51)
- Health Insurance Plan of Greater New York, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 1)
- Histadrut, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 2)
- Hospital (Joint), 1951 (Box 184, Folder 3)
- Housing, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 4)
- Hughes - Breese Unemployment Insurance Bill, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 5)
- H: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 6)
- International Longshoremen's Association, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 7)
- Invitations, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 8)
- I: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 9)
- Jewish War Veterans of the United States of America, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 10)
- K: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 11)
- Department of Labor, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 12)
- Labor Chronicle, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 13)
- Labor's League for Political Education, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 14)
- Lacey, Martin T.: President of Central Trades and Labor Council of Greater New York, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 15)
- Legislative, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 16)
- Lincoln Birthday Dinner-Dance, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 17)
- L: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 18)
- Mayor's Committee on Unity of New York City, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 19)
- M: Miscellaneous (I), 1951 (Box 184, Folder 20)
- M: Miscellaneous (II), 1951 (Box 184, Folder 21)
- New York City Federation of Labor Bulletins, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 22)
- New York City Federation of Labor, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 23)
- New York State Unemployment Insurance Law, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 24)
- Non-Partisan, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 25)
- N: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 26)
- O: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 27)
- Police Athletic League (P.A.L.), 1951 (Box 184, Folder 28)
- Post Office, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 29)
- P: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 30)
- Radio, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 31)
- Red Cross, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 32)
- Resolutions, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 33)
- R: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 34)
- Sanitation, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 35)
- Seaway, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 36)
- Senate and Assembly - State of New York, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 37)
- S: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 38)
- Teachers, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 39)
- Telegrams and Condolences, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 40)
- T: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 41)
- Union Label, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 42)
- United States National Committee for UNESCO, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 43)
- U: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 44)
- Veterans, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 45)
- Wage Stabilization Board, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 46)
- W: Miscellaneous, 1951 (Box 184, Folder 47)
- General files: includes Brotherhood Party and Civil Rights, 1963-1964 (Box 185)
- General files: includes Anti-Poverty Board, Civil Rights, and World Trade Center, 1964-1965 (Box 186)
- General files: includes Van Arsdale, Harry, 1964 (Box 187)
- General files, 1962 (Box 188)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1942 (Box 189, Folder 1)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1943 (Box 189, Folder 2)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1944 (Box 189, Folder 3)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1945 (Box 189, Folder 4)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1946 (Box 189, Folder 5)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1947 (Box 189, Folder 6)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1948 (Box 189, Folder 7)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1949 (Box 189, Folder 8)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1950 (Box 189, Folder 9)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1933 (Box 190, Folder 1)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1934 (Box 190, Folder 2)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1935 (Box 190, Folder 3)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1936 (Box 190, Folder 4)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1937 (Box 190, Folder 5)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1938 (Box 190, Folder 6)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1939 (Box 190, Folder 7)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1940 (Box 190, Folder 8)
- Central Trades and Labor Council Executive Board and Regular Meetings Minutes, 1941 (Box 190, Folder 9)
- AFL-CIO to Coalition of Labor Union Women, 1992 (Box 191)
- Black Heritage to Democratic National Convention, 1992 (Box 192)
- General files: includes Union locals files, 1993 (Box 193)
- Asian (1993);NY State AFL-CIO (1993); Political (1994), 1993-1994 (Box 194)
- Coalition of Business, Labor and community Organizations of NY to Ellis Island, 1994 (Box 195)
- General files, 1993 (Box 196)
- General files: includes South Africa and POW/MIA, 1994 (Box 197)
- General files, 1990, 1994 (Box 198)
- General files, 1993 (Box 199)
- Delegates to Delegates Body Meetings (1993);Unions: Teachers to Unions: Utilities Workers (1994), 1993-1994 (Box 200)
- General files: includes AFL-CIO Photos, 1994 (Box 201)
- National Health Policy to NYCCLC: Trade Union Leadership Institute, 1991 (Box 202)
- Employment Application and Resumes to International Labor Organization, 1994 (Box 203)
- Puerto Rico to Unions: Flight Attendants, 1994 (Box 204)
- AFL-CIO files;United Way of NY to Voter Registration, 1994 (Box 205)
- Health to Italian Hospital Society, 1994 (Box 206)
- General files (includes Lincoln's Birthday to National Consumers League), 1990-1991 (Box 207)
- General files, 1991 (Box 208)
- General files, 1991 (Box 209)
- General files, 1991 (Box 210)
- Affiliation to Circular Letters, 1993 (Box 211)
- AFL-CIO Executive Council to Ethnic Coalition, 1993 (Box 212)
- General files, 1993 (Box 213)
- Jacobsen, Ted: Jewish Labor Committee to Legislation, 1993 (Box 214)
- General files: mostly Jacobsen, Ted, 1993 (Box 215)
- General files, 1991 (Box 216)
- General files, 1990 (Box 217)
- General files (1990); New York City Central Labor Council (1992), 1990, 1992 (Box 218)
- New York City Central Labor Council: Executive Board to Oldtimers, 1992 (Box 219)
- AFL-CIO files; Workplace Literacy, 1991 (Box 220)
- Political Committees to Pro-Choice, 1992 (Box 221)
- United Way (1990); AFL-CIO to Disabled (1994), 1990, 1994 (Box 222)
- Manhattan Political Committee; Occupational Education to POW/MIA, 1991-1992 (Box 223)
- General files, 1991 (Box 224)
- General files, 1991 (Box 225)
- AFL-CIO to China, 1993 (Box 226)
- AFL-CIO to NYCCLC Executive Board, 1959-1961 (Box 227)
- General files: includes Local Union Correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 228)
- Dinner Dance to Irish, 1996 (Box 229)
- AFL-CIO to Building and Construction, 2001 (Box 230)
- AFL-CIO to America Needs a Raise;Irish, 1996 (Box 231)
- Circular Letters to Dinner Dance (1996); Car Service to Databases (2001), 1996, 2001 (Box 232)
- Delegates Body Meetings to Printing Trades, 1996 (Box 233)
- Privatization to Unemployment Insurance, 1996 (Box 234)
- International Labor Communications Association to Italian Hospital Society, 1998 (Box 235)
- Dinner Dance to Immigration, 1998 (Box 236)
- Unions: Carpenters to Unions: Writers Guild, 1999 (Box 237)
- Jewish Labor Committee to Labor News, 1997 (Box 238)
- Dinner Dance to Hispanics, 1999 (Box 239)
- Printing Trades to Unions: Stage Employees, 1998 (Box 240)
- Invitations to Labor Day (1999); Kelber, Harry to NECO Forum (1999); Labor Day (2000), 1999-2000 (Box 241)
- Dinner Dance; Labor Day to Kosovo, 1999 (Box 242)
- Union Label to Unions: Letter Carriers, 1996 (Box 243)
- Political Action Committee to United Way, 1999 (Box 244)
- New York City Central Labor Council Executive Board attendance records and minutes, 1959-1980s (Box 245)
- Labor News to Workplace Fairness (1997); Political to Political Action Committee (1998), 1997-1998 (Box 246)
- America Needs a Raise to Baseball, 1996 (Box 247)
- AFL-CIO to Alitalia; Immigration to Invitations, 1999 (Box 248)
- Asian-Pacific-American Labor Alliance to Day of Action, 1998 (Box 249)
- Baseball to Children (1996); AFL-CIO to American Red Cross (1998), 1996, 1998 (Box 250)
- Jewish Labor Committee to Labor Archives; School-to-Work to Workmen's Circle, 1998 (Box 251)
- Buttons, Undated (Box 252)
- Labor Day to Legislation: General (1996); Labor Day (1998), 1996, 1998 (Box 253)
- Living Wage Bill to Workers' Compensation (1996);Some "W" files (1999-2000), 1996, 1999-2000 (Box 254)
- Asian-Pacific-American Labor Alliance to Delegates, 1997 (Box 255)
- Dinner Dance to United Way (1997); Jacobsen, Ted: B'nai B'rith to Jacobsen, Ted: Occupational Education (1998), 1997-1998 (Box 256)
- Association for a Better NY to Africa, 2002-2003 (Box 257)
- AFL-CIO to American Red Cross (1997);US Savings Bonds to Workers' Memorial Day (1999); Asian-Pacific-American Labor Alliance to Boy Scouts (2002), 1997, 1999, 2002 (Box 258)
- Coalition for Community Services to Mobilization: May 12, 1999 (Box 259)
- Invitations to Jacobsen, Ted: Personal, 2000 (Box 260)
- Photos to Rehabilitation, 2000 (Box 261)
- Irish to Jacobsen, Ted: Workmen's Circle, 1997 (Box 262)
- American Red Cross to Circular Letters, 1999 (Box 263)
- Asian-Pacific-American Labor Alliance to Catholic Charities, 2000 (Box 264)
- Newspaper Clippings to Photos, 2000 (Box 265)
- Employment to Invitations, 1997 (Box 266)
- Mobilization: May 12, 1999 to Per Capita Initiative (Box 267)
- AFL-CIO to American Red Cross, 2000 (Box 268)
- Catholic to Invitations, 2000 (Box 269)
- Jewish Labor Committee to Labor Day, 2000 (Box 270)
- Unions: State, County, and Municipal Workers to Unions: Writers Guild (1998); Dinner (1999); Political to Prevailing Wage (1999), 1998-1999 (Box 271)
- Unions: Locomotive Engineers to Unions: Writers Guild, 1997 (Box 272)
- Unions: Retail, Wholesale and Department Stores to Van Arsdale, Harry: Memorial Association, 2000 (Box 273)
- Finances, 1994-1995 (Box 274)
- Labor Day (1996); Discrimination to Emerald Isle (1997); Safety and Health to Workers' Memorial Day (1998), 1996-1998 (Box 275)
- Safety and Health to Unions: Public Employees, 2000 (Box 276)
- Israel to John Jay College (1996); Labor Day (1998) (1 file); Van Arsdale, Harry: Memorial Association to Workers' Memorial Day (2000), 1996, 1998-2000 (Box 277)
- Finances (1994-1995); School-to-Work (1996), 1994-1996 (Box 278)
- Materials related to Immigrant Freedom Ride, 2003 (Box 279)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 280)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 281)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 282)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 283)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 284)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 285)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 286)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 287)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 288)
- Undescribed, undated (Box 289)
- VHS and Betacam Tapes of Various Events, 1992-2004, undated (Box 290)
- VHS Tapes (mostly from 2003 Freedom Ride Rally), Audio Cassettes, Immigration Sub-Committee Banner, Plaque, and T-Shirts, 2003-2005, undated (Box 291)
- Artifacts, pins, stickers, hats, flyers, passes, book on collecting political americana, 1989-1995, undated (Box 292)
- 2 scrapbooks containing newspaper clippings from the 1960s, 1960-1969 (Box 293)
- Banner, Undated; cuid854; 1 item (Item WAG.049.cuid854)
  Quilts.
- Van Arsdale clippings scrapbook, 1958-1964 (Box 294, Folder 1)
- Olga Diaz award, NYC proclamation, 1967, 2000 (Box 294, Folder 2)
- Picket signs, post 9/11, 2007 (Box 294, Folder 3)
- Photograph of testimonial dinner in honor of Eddie Ott, 1944-11-04 (Box 294, Folder 4)
- Stickers and Graphic, Undated (Box 294, Folder 5)
- T-shirt (Box 295)
- Unprocessed videos (Box 296)
- Unprocessed Oversize Materials, 1959-2001 (Box Shared Tamiment 142, Folder 11)
- Archived Websites, September 2007-ongoing; 4 websites in 4 archived websites. (Box Electronic Records)
  Scope and Content Note
  The New York City Central Labor Council (NYCCLC) is a non-profit labor membership organization that supports and advocates for workers in New York City and is affiliated with over 400 local unions in both public and private sectors. Capture of the website began in 2007 and consisted of infromation about their officers and staff; events; community services related to career day, summer camps, substance abuse, and strike rapid response; committees related to housing, healthcare, and retirees (New York City Alliance for Retired Americans); press releases; speeches, biographies of officers; photographs from events; and other labor news. News is focused on labor marches and rallies; bargaining and strike notices; midterm and presidential elections; Council elections; promotion of the Employee Free Choice Act and Health and Compensation Act; and Council's responses to the State of the City addresses.
  In early 2012, the website redesigned to include information on the executive board, officers, and staff members; member benefits; news regarding contracts and bargaining; Hurricane Sandy relief work; prevailing wage agreements; Con Edison lockout; and other news on affiliate unions.
  In April 2013, the NYCCLC reformatted to its current iteration (as of January 2022). The website is divided into sections related to issues, news, events, and resources. The constituency groups affiliated with the Council include Asian Pacific American Labor Alliance, NYC Labor Council for Latin American Advancement, and the A. Philip Randolph Institute. Issues focused on by the Council include jobs and the economy, healthcare, retirement security, work and family, trade, education, civil and workplace rights, immigration, and job safety. In 2019, the issues expande to include climate and political and legislative action. THe webiste also includes union vendors, union affliates, staff and officiers, image galleries of events, and press releases.
  NYC Labor Votes is a political project of the New York City Central Labor Council. The website contains information on how to register to vote, ranked choice voting, labor endorsed candidates, endorsed candidate profiles, and news stories about local New York City politics.
  Climate Jobs NY is a coalition of labor unions advocating for clean energy union jobs. The coalition consists of the New York City Central Labor Council, Building and Construction Trades Council of Greater New York, Service Employees International Union, District Council 37 of AFSCME, Building & Construction Trades of Nassau & Suffolk Counties, Communications Workers of America District 1, IBEW Local 3, IUOE Local 30, District Council 9 of the International Union of Painters and Allied Trades, Laborers Local 79, Long Island Federation of Labor, New York City District Council of Carpenters and Joiners of America, New York State AFL-CIO, New York State Nurses Association, 32BJ SEIU, Transport Workers Union (TWU) Local 100, United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry of the United States and Canada, and the Utility Workers Union of America. The website contains information on the Carbon Free and Healthy Schools campaign, offshore wind energy in New York, annual reports, climate stimulus polling report, the 2021 Climate Jobs Summit, and a monthly newsletter.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.
  Accruals
  Until 2020, http://www.nycclc.org/ was accrued semiannually. In 2020, http://www.nycclc.org/ was accrued twice a month. In 2021, http://www.nycclc.org/ was accrued monthly.
  http://www.workingtogether.nyc/ is accrued quarterly. https://www.climatejobsny.org/ is accrued semiannually.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nycclc.org, climatejobsny.org, and workingtogether.nyc in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- General Files, Correspondence, 2006-2008 (Box 297)
- General Files, Mailings, 2004-2007 (Box 298)
- Financial Materials, Speeches, 2007 (Box 299)
- General Files; Rally, Convention, and Event Materials, 2006-2017 (Box 300)
- Event Files, 2009-2015 (Box 301)
- Event Files, 2010-2018 (Box 302)
- General Files, 2009-2012 (Box 303)
- General Files, 2010-2018 (Box 304)
- General Files, 2008-2016 (Box 305)
- General Files, 2010-2016 (Box 306)
- Labor Day Parade, Young Workers Conference, 2010-2014 (Box 307)
- Labor Day Parade, 2013-2015 (Box 308, Box Shared Tamiment Accessions 005, Folder 3-4)
- Labor Day Parade, 2015-2016 (Box 309)
- Labor Day Parade, Constitutional Convention, 2015-2017 (Box 310, Box Shared Tamiment Accessions 005, Folder 5)
- Workshops, Meetings, Conventions, 2012-2018 (Box 311)
- Publications, Event Files, 2010-2017 (Box 312)
- Publications, Union Files, 2009-2018 (Box 313)
- General Files, Union Files, 2011-2016 (Box 314, Box Shared Tamiment Accessions 004 (Born-digital), Disc TW_WAG_049_1)
- General Files, Internship Files, 2011-2019 (Box 315)
- General Files, Executive Board Meeting Photographs, 2009-2016 (Box 316)
- General Files, Constitution and Bylaws, 2011 Officers' Elections, 2009-2018 (Box 317)
- General Files, Directories, Advisory Council Attendance Book, 1986-2011 (Box 318, Box Shared Tamiment Accessions 004 (Born-digital), Disk TW_WAG_049_2, Disc TW_WAG_049_3)
- Executive Board Attendance Book, 1994-2007 (Box 319, Box Shared Tamiment Accessions 005, Folder 6)
- ILGWU Sweater, undated (Box 320)